Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 27-nen kimitsu honsho o), 1894; 409 frames. (Reel 3)
  Documents and texts of a loan contract from the Bank of Japan to the Korean government signed on Mar. 30, 1895. Reports from Japanese Minister in Korea Komura to Acting Japanese Foreign Minister Saionji relating to the removal of the Korean King to the Russian Legation in Seoul; insurrection in Ky0nggi Province; new Korean cabinet members; the Royal Proclamation concerning the removal of the royal court to D0ksu Palace; and the activities ofS0 Chae-p'il, O Yun-jung and other members of the new cabinet. Correspondence between Japanese Foreign Minister Mutsu and Japanese Minister in Korea Komura relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Korea; the activities of the Russian Minister in Seoul; Russian military training program for Korea. Jan. 9 - Dec. 28, 1896.
  Missing frames: 260-262. Illegible fr.: 94, 143, 152, 156, 157, 258, 265, 266, 334, 336, 337, 357, 368, 384. 194-1, -2 in Korean. 249 is followed by 249-1, -2; 250 by 250-1, -2; 251 by 251-1, -2; 341 by 341-1, -2; 359 by 359-1, -2; 392 by a new series, numbered 1 through 12, English. 75a contains the Royal Proclamation of the Korean Emperor in English (Japanese translation in 73, 76, 78).
- Confidential official correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office, (Meiji 29-nen honsho rai kimitsu koshin), 1896; 198 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 33.
  Confidential letter received from Acting Japanese Foreign Minister Saionji concerning the official report on Korea by Japanese Minister in the United States Kurino Shin'ichiro. Documents relating to the conversations between Japanese Minister in Russia Nishi Tokujiro and the Head of the Asiatic Bureau of the Russian Foreign Ministry concerning Korea. Copy of the speech of the Chancellor of Exchequer of Great Britain concerning Anglo-Russian relations in the Far East. Documents relating to the removal of the Korean King to the Russian Legation. Copy of the report sent from Japanese Minister in Great Britain Kato Takaaki to the Home Office relating to the conversation between Kato and British Foreign Secretary Salisbury concerning Korea. Documents relating to the Seoul-Inchon R. R., and Japanese-American relations concerning this railroad. Documents relating to the case of Japanese Minister in Korea Miura Goro. Confidential documents relating to the Russian Trans-Manchurian railroad. Confidential letters received from Acting Japanese Foreign Minister Saionji concerning the activities of Pak Y0ng-hyo and other Korean political refugees in Japan. Jan. 14 - Dec. 15, 1896.
  Missing frames: 18, 87-89, 101. Illegible fr.: 15-17, 19-23, 29, 58, 79, 83, 86, 93, 170-172, 174-176, 186, 187, 190, 192, 196. Last two frames unnumbered. 186 is followed by 186-1; 196 by 196-1. 15-35, 184-187 in English.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, --Part I (Meiji 29-nen kakkan ofuku jo), 1896; 33 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 34.
  Official correspondence of Japanese Minister in Korea Komura with the Japanese Consulate at W0nsan concerning the changes in the Korean Cabinet on Feb. 12, 1896. Report of Consul Kato Masuo to the new Japanese Minister in Korea Hara Satoshi dated Sept. 17, 1896 concerning the difficulties of Japanese ginseng merchants in Kaes0ng. Text of the Japanese-Korean agreement on the judicial procedure for Japanese nationals. Tables showing the number of foreign residents in Korea in 1896.
  Missing frame: 34. Illegible fr.: 15a, 26. 15a, 18a, 30a contain tables. 24, 25, 27b, 28a in Korean.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, --Part II (Meiji 29-nen kakkan ofuku chu), 1896; 29 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 35.
  Report from Japanese Consul in Inchon Hagiwara Shuichi to Japanese Minister in Korea Komura dated May 9, 1896 concerning the trial of a Japanese subject charged with illegal monetary transactions with Min Yong-sun, the Korean Superintendent at the Y0ng'yang mint. Report from Hagiwara to Japanese Minister in Korea Hara dated Aug. 25, 1896 concerning public attitude toward the Japanese in Inchon area; and the construction of a Russian coal dump at Inchon. Tables showing the trade between Inchon and Poyngyang in July, 1896.
  Generally illegible. 22 is followed by 22-1. 24b-27a contain tables.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 29-nen kakkan ofuku), 1896; 7 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 36.
  Report submitted by a Japanese official to the Japanese Consulate in W0nsan concerning his trip to Unggi and Ky0nghung Bay areas in July, 1896. The report contains descriptions of Unggi and KyOnghung areas and the attitude of Koreans towards the Japanese and the Russians.
- Documents relating to the death of the [Korean] Queen, and the removal of the King to the Russian Legation, (Meiji 28, 9-nen [UNK]Oki hogyo Rokan igyo ikken), 1896-1897; 31 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 37. Documents relating to the reorganization of the Korean government. Memorandum on Russo Japanese negotiations concerning the return of the Korean King from the Russian Legation to the Palace. Communications from Japanese Minister in Korea Miura and Korean Foreign Minister Yi Chong-ung concerning the political crisis in Korea. Personal letter of Mutsu Munemitsu concerning Pak Y0ng-hyo and other Korean political refugees in Japan. Mar. 23 - Oct. 10, 1896.
  Generally legible. 24 is followed by 24-1, -2, -3, -4. 9-23 in English.
- Secret regular Japanese-language telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 28-nen kimitsu tsuju wabun dempo ofuku), 1895; 329 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 38.
  Documents relating to a bond issue in Korea; the maintenance of telegraphic lines and of the postal service; Japanese settlements in Chinnamp'o and Mokp'o; the appointment of Miura Goro as the Japanese Minister to Korea; the clash between the court circles and the cabinet; and the departure of Pak Y0ng-hyo and others from Korea to Japan by a Japanese vessel. Documents relating to the Regent Taew0ngun's coup d'état and the assassination of Queen Min; the arrival of Russian and American troops in Seoul; and the attitude of the British, Russian, German, and American ministers in Korea regarding the coup d'état. Jan. 15, 1895. - Feb. 29, 1896.
  Missing frames: 13, 37, 48. Illegible fr.: 6, 11, 20, 65, 66, 78, 177, 181, 252, 316. 3 is followed by an unnumbered frame. 174 is followed by 174-1.
- Copies of Japanese-language telegrams to and from the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 29-nen wabun denshin ofuku hikae), 1896; 144 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 39.
  Documents relating to the land leased by the Russian government in Inchon; the arrival of French and Russian warships in Inchon; the arrival of Russian troops in Seoul; the popular uprising in Ch'unch'0n and Pyongyang areas; the return of the Russian Minister in Korea to Russia; the arrival of American troops in Seoul. Confidential correspondence from Acting Japanese Foreign Minister Saionji to Japanese Minister in Korea Komura relating to the conversations held by Japanese Minister to Russia Nishi with members of the Russian government concerning Korea. Documents relating to Song Ki-wun and other secret envoys of the Korean King to Russia; the withdrawal of foreign troops from Korea; the mobilization of the Chinese troops near Iju; and the French proposal for the construction of a railroad between Seoul and W0nsan. Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Komura and Japanese Foreign Minister Mutsu concerning the Russian attitude toward Korea. Jan. 1 - Dec. 26, 1896.
  Illegible frames: 22, 71, 80, 104, 109, 131, 141. 6, 15, 17, 20, 23, 27, 39, 65, 69 illegible in part.
- Documents concerning damages suffered by Japanese [in Korea], (Meiji 29-nen homp0jin higai ni kansuru shorui), 1896; 150 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 40.
  Documents relating to the damage to the Japanese and to Japanese property during the popular uprising known as the "Seoul Incident" of November, 1895. Mar. 9, 1896 - Jan. 29, 1905.
  Illegible frames: 83, 131. 8 is followed by 8 -1, -2; 9 by 9 -1; 13 by 13 -1; 17 by 17 -1; 21 by 21 -1; 89 by 89 -1. 88 and 89 on one frame. 110-117, 129 in Korean.
- Diplomatic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean government, (Meiji 29-nen Gaibu orai), 1896; 162 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 41.
  Communications between Japanese Minister in Korea Komura and Korean Foreign Ministers Kim Yun-sik and Yi Wan-yong concerning Japanese loans to Korea and the employment of Japanese military and police personnel by the Korean government. Communications between Japanese Minister in Korea Hara and Yi Wan-yong concerning the tariff question at Pusan and protection of the Japanese nationals in Korea. Communications between Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato and Yi Wan-yong concerning the ginseng trade. Jan. 16, Nov. 22, 1896.
  6 is imperfect. 4 is followed by 4 -1; 15 by 15 -1; 16 by 16 -1; 17 by 17 -1; 21 by 21 -1; 22 by 22 -1; 29 by 29 -1, -2; 30 by 30 -1; 31 by 31 -1; 35 by 35-1, -2; 39 by 39 -1; 40 by 40 -1; 43 by 43 -1; 44 by 44 -1; 45 by 45 -1.
- Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 29-nen kimitsu kakkan ofuku), 1896; 102 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 42.
  Documents relating to the action taken by the Korean government against the pro-Japanese party members and pro-Taew0ngun elements; the coinage of money in Korea; and a plan for the commercial recovery of Inchon. Record of conversations between Yi My0ng-ik and Han Ch'0l-ha, secret agents of the Korean government, with a Japanese police officer on Oct. 15, 1896, concerning the assassins of Queen Min: Pak Y0ng-hyo and others who were involved in her death. Documents relating to the appearance of Russian warships and whaling boats in Korean waters near W0nsan. Apr. 8 - Nov. 20, 1896.
  Illegible frames: 1, 2, 4, 11, 13, 33-40, 42, 49, 53-56, 64, 69, 98. 61, 68, 84, 86, 91, 93, 98, 99 imperfect.
- Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 30-nen kimitsu kakkan ofuku), 1897; 46 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 43.
  Documents relating to the opening of Mokp'o and Chinnamp'o in Sept. 1897, and the regulations governing the foreign settlements there. Confidential report from Japanese Consul at Pusan Ijuin Hikokichi to Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo dated Nov. 25, 1897 concerning the arrival of the Russian fleet at Pusan. The request of Consul Hisamizu Saburo for the dispatch of Japanese warships to Mokp'o, dated Nov. 25, 1897. Confidential report dated Apr. 23, 1898 from Japanese Consul at Inchon Ishii Kikujiro to Kato concerning personnel changes in the Russian Legation guards in Seoul.
  Illegible frames: 8, 14, 17, 18, 27, 30, 41. 13, 14, 33, 34 contain maps. 16b-18 contain tables. 5-7 in English and Japanese.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office, (Meiji 30-nen kimitsu honsho ofuku), 1897; 173 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 44.
  Confidential correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo and Japanese Foreign Minister Okuma relating to the return of the Korean King to Ky0ng'un Palace, the struggle for power between Korean cabinet members and the eunuchs at the Imperial Palace; and the Russo-Korean agreement on the lease of land on W0lmido Island off Inchon Bay. Documents relating to the protection of Chinese nationals in Korea; the friction between Russian military envoy to Korea Putiata and the Korean Imperial Guards; the texts of the contract for the employment of a Russian engineer, Ulemnov, by the Korean Government; the 30,000,000 yen loan to Korea by the Bank of Japan; and the mine operated by a German promoter. Texts of the agreement between Korea and Russia concerning the Russian military training program in Korea. Records of conversations between Japanese representative Hoshi and John Sill, the American Minister to Korea, concerning the Russian military training program in Korea. Summary of conversations between Sill and Horace N. Allen, Secretary of the American Legation, concerning Russian Minister Weber's plan in Korea. Jan. 16 - May 11, 1897.
  170, 171 on the same frame. 25-29, 168-170 in English; 97, 98 in Korean.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, --Part II (Meiji 30-nen kakkan ofuku ge), 1897; 166 frames.
  Box/Folder 1: 46.
  Documents relating to the Russian Fishing Company at Vladivostok and its activities in Korean waters. Summary of conversations with Captain Yi Ki-gang of "Hy0nik Ho" concerning the activities of Russian and German vessels in Korean waters. Reports from the Japanese Consul at W0nsan concerning the arrival and departure of foreign warships.
  Illegible frames: 4, 14, 16, 17, 47, 60-62, 66, 68, 70, 75, 80, 81, 86, 93, 94, 99, 100. 33, 103 in Korean.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office, (Meiji 30-nen kimitsu honsho raishin), 1897; 190 frames. (Reel 4)
  Box/Folder 1: 48.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato Masuo to Japanese Foreign Minister Okuma concerning Russian ship-building at Vladivostok. Documents relating to the activities of Pak Y0ng-hyo in Japan; the Russo-Japanese convention of May 14, 1897 concerning Korea; the Russian economic mission to China and Korea; the trial of persons involved in the removal of the Korean King to the Russian Legation; and the departure of Russian Minister Weber from Seoul. Instructions to Japanese military commanders in Seoul, Pusan, and W0nsan. Documents relating to the employment of Russian military advisers by the Korean government; copy of a letter from U.S. Secretary of State John Sherman to American Minister in Korea John Sill, dated May 6, 1897, concerning the appointment of Russian military advisers by the Korean government. Documents relating to the attitude and activities of Minister Sill; the speech of the British Deputy Foreign Secretary concerning Korea; the arrival of Russian fleet at Korea; and the employment of Möllendorff by the Korean government. Jan. 28 - Dec. 27, 1897.
  Illegible frames: 23, 58, 61, 62, 105, 118, 127. 150, 151 on one frame; 161, 162 on one frame. 39-41, 100, 113-115, 151-153, 160, 161, 188-191 in English; 104, 105 in French.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 30-nen kimitsu honsho oshin), 1897; 169 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 49.
  Confidential documents relating to the Russian trained Royal Palace Guard; Russian Colonel Putiata; the discovery of a plot to overthrow the Korean cabinet, and the trial of the conspirators. Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Minister in Korea with the Home Office concerning Japanese financial aid to Kerim Chang'0ptan; and the political activities of Taew0ngun. Summary of conversation between Japanese Chargé d'Affaires in Korea Kato Masuo and Korean Foreign Minister Min Y0ng-hwan concerning the political situation in Korea and the attitude of British, Russian, and American ministers in Korea. Documents relating to the request of the Korean government to Russian Minister in Korea Weber concerning the sending of Russian military officers to train the Korean army; the appointment of Horace N. Allen as American Minister to Korea; the establishment of British Legation in Korea; and the lease of Ch0ly0ngdo Island by Russia. June 1 - Dec. 21, 1897.
  Missing frame: 145. Illegible fr.: 161. 153, 154 on one frame. 18, 102, 103, 133-137, 154-156, 159, 160 in Korean; 161 in English.
- Documents relating to the summoning of Yi Yun-yong. Documents relating to the Tonghak Movement, appendix: documents relating to the dispatch of Japanese police force (Meiji 27-nen Ri In-yo shokan no ken. Meiji 27-nen Togakuto ni kansuru ken; fu junsa haken), 1894; 25 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 50.
  Diplomatic notes exchanged between Korean Foreign Minister Kim Yun-sik and Japanese Minister in Korea Inoue concerning the summoning of Yi Yun-yong by the Japanese police Nov. 8, - Dec. 7, 1894.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office, (Meiji 30-nen honsho oraishin), 1897; 100 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 51.
  Correspondence to and from Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato Masuo and Japanese Foreign Ministers Okuma and Nishi relating to the change of the name of Korea from Chos0n to Tae Han and the adoption of the Imperial title by the Korean King. Documents relating to the dismissal of Korean Minister in France Min Y0ng-ik and Franco-Korean relations; confidential correspondence from Japanese Chargé d'Affaires in Russia Motono Ichiro to the Japanese Home Office concerning the secret Russo-Chinese treaty, and the attitude of the British government and the English press; and the implementation of Article XVI of the Japanese-American Treaty of Commerce and Navigation of 1894. Dispatch of Kir. Alekseev and Lieutenant Garfield by the Russian government to Korea; and Russian press articles relating to the relations between Russia and Japan in Korea. Correspondence of the Japanese ministers in European capitals with Okuma relating to the Franco-Russian Alliance. Jan. 6 - Dec. 28, 1897. 61, 64 in English.
- Documents relating to the opening of Mokp'o, Chinnamp'o, and the Taedong River, (Meiji 30-nen Moppo, Chinnanmpo, Daidoko kaiko ikken), 1897; 211 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 52.
  Agreements between Korea and Japan relating to the opening of Mokp'o and Chinnamp'o, and the preliminary land survey in these areas. Texts of "Regulations for the Foreign Settlements at Chinnamp'o and Mokp'o" (draft) and "Regulations for the Foreign Settlements at Chinnamp'o and Mokp'o" signed on Oct. 16, 1897 by Korea with Japan, the United States, Russia, Great Britain, France, and Germany. Jan. 18 - Nov. 13, 1897.
  Missing frames: 162, 212. Illegible fr.: 200, 201. 49-55, 102, 103, 110, 111, 120, 121 contain maps. 139-141, 181-188, 193, 194, 197, 198, 200-203 in English.
- Diplomatic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean government, (Meiji 30-nen Gaibu orai), 1897; 62 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 53.
  Communications between Japanese Charge d'Affaires Kato Masuo and Korean Foreign Minister Yi Wan-yong relating to the Russo-Japanese Memorandum signed on May 14, 1896 and its effect on Korea's sovereignty and independence. Documents relating to the Inchon foreign settlement. Jan. 12 - Dec. 31, 1897.
  7 is followed by 7 -1, -2. 57 partially in Korean.
- Reports of the Japanese Legation in Korea to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 30-nen honsho ofuku hokoku), 1897; 171 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 54.
  Consular reports on Korean governmental affairs; the memorial submitted to the Korean King by Yim C[UNK]hi-su and others concerning the King's return to the Palace from the Russian Legation, and the summary of the Royal edict in reply to the memorial. Documents relating to the reorganization of the Korean government and the Russian influence on the Korean King. Jan. 18 - Dec. 27, 1897.
- Copies of confidential Japanese-language telegrams to and from the Japanese Legation in Korea in (Meiji 30-nen kimitsu wabun denshin ofuku hikae), 1897; 136 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 55.
  Copies of confidential telegrams exchanged between Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato Masuo and Japanese Foreign Minister Okuma. Jan. 4 - Dec. 28, 1897.
  Illegible frame: 35.
- Secret documents of the Japanese Legation in Korea during the appointment of Kato Masuo as the Japanese Minister to Korea, (Meiji 30-nen Kato Koshi jidai gokuhi shorui), 1897; 148 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 56.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo and Japanese Vice-Minister of Foreign Affairs Komura relating to the replacement of J. M. Brown, British adviser to the Korean government, by the Russian adviser, Alekseev, and the latter's activities in Korea. Documents relating to Japanese troops in Korea; the secret Russo-Korean military and financial agreements of Aug. 1, 1896 and the Korean government crisis which followed the conclusion of these secret agreements. Summary of a verbal memorial of Yi Yun-yong, Pak Ch0ng-yang, and Yi Wan-yong to the Throne concerning Russo-Korean relations. Correspondence from Japanese Foreign Minister Nishi to Kato relating to the telegram received from the Japanese Minister at St. Petersburg concerning independent Russian action in dealing with the Korean government. Jan. 27 - Nov. 13, 1897.
  Illegible frames: 127, 132, 133, 134a, 135b. 2 different frames numbered 63. 12-14, 15a, 40, 41, 94, 120-141 in English; 15b, 32-34, 37, 71, 72, 76, 81 in Korean; 118, 119 in French.
- Correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 31-nen kaku ryojikan raishin), 1898; 73 frames.
  Box/Folder 2; 57.
  Documents relating to the opening of Masan; the arrival of a Russian military mission in Korea; and political conditions in Korea near the Russian border. A detailed report on the geography, topography, and economic and social conditions of the city of S0ngjin. Documents relating to the trial of Yoshita Masutaro in connection with his illegal commerical relations with the Russians. Report on the rice riot in Pyongyang. Apr. 9 - Dec. 28, 1898.
  10, 51b, 52 contain maps. 57b, 58 in English.
- Copies of European-language telegrams to and from the Japanese Legation in Korea, --Part VI (Ji Meiji 28-nen itaru Meiji 30-nen obun dempo ofuku hikae, roku.), 1895-1897; 96 frames
  Box/Folder 2: 58.
  Copies of English-langauge telegrams between the Japanese Foreign Minister and the German, French, and Russian ministers in Japan. Documents relating to the return of the Liaotung Peninsula to China. May 9, 1895 - Mar. 17, 1899.
  Two frames numbered 41. 90 is followed by 90 -1, -2, -3, -4, -5. All except 41a, 68a in English.
- Correspondence between the Japanese Legation in Korea and the Home Office, (Meiji 31-nen honsho oraishin), 1898; 92 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 59.
  Documents relating to the opening of S0ngjin, Kunsan, Masan, and Pyongyang; Japanese technical aid to Korea; the usage of Japanese coins in Korea; the Independence Club of Korea; the reorganization of the Korean government; and Pak Y0ng-hyo. Correspondence between Japanese Foreign Minister Nishi and Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato Masuo concerning the Russo-Chinese treaty dealing with Port Arthur and Dairen. May 20 - Nov. 10, 1898.
  Missing frame: 83. 19-21 in Korean.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office, (Meiji 31-nen kimitsu honsho raishin), 1898; 126 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 60.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Foreign Minister Nishi to Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Kato Masuo relating to the dismissal of J. M. Brown, the British financial adviser to the Korean government; the Russian acquisition of land in Chinnamp'o, Mokp'o, and on the island of Ch0ly0ng. Documents relating to the Rosen-Nishi Agreement of Apr. 25, 1898; the Sino-Korean treaty negotiations; and the opening of S0ngjin and Pyongyang. Jan. 12 - Dec. 23, 1898.
  Illegible frames: 36, 42a, 43a, 44a, 48, 49a, 50a, 54a, 98b, 99, 100. 27 is followed by 27 -1, -2, -3; 117 by 117 -1, -2, -3, -4. 9b, 10a, 117, 117 -1, -2, -3, -4 contain maps. 17 in Russian; 18, 67a, 68b in English; 32b, 33a in French.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 31-nen kimitsu honsho oshin), 1898; 197 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 61.